<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>math on nathan naveen</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/tags/math/</link><description>Recent content in math on nathan naveen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 11:04:23 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nathannaveen.dev/tags/math/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leetcode 223</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-223/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 11:04:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-223/</guid><description>223. Rectangle Area
The main idea of this solution is to find the area of each indivigual rectangle and then add them together. After that subtract the overlap of both of them.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t understand the ABCDRectangle and the EFGHRectangle then look at the following images:
We can have the example:
Let us start of with the ABCDRectangle:
When we do the equation (D - B) * (C - A) we are basicly doing width * length.</description></item><item><title>Leetcode 908</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-908/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 15:47:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-908/</guid><description>908. Smallest Range I
func smallestRangeI(A []int, K int) int { max, min := A[0], A[0] for _, i := range A { if i &amp;gt; max {max = i} if i &amp;lt; min {min = i} } if max-min-2*K &amp;gt; 0 { return max - min - 2 * K } return 0 }</description></item><item><title>Leetcode 1385</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-1385/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 13:25:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-1385/</guid><description>1385. Find the Distance Value Between Two Arrays
The idea of this solution is to iterate through arr1 and then inside each iteration iterate through arr2. If the absolute value of arr1[i] - arr2[j] is smaller than or equal to d, we know that arr1[i] can&amp;rsquo;t be added to the resulting counter, so we can just break from the loop.
There is a abs function because math.Abs takes longer. When using math.</description></item><item><title>Leetcode 645</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-645/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 11:27:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-645/</guid><description>645. Set Mismatch
The idea of this solution is to add every number in the array nums to another array called temp. Next we go through the array temp and check whether the number of a certain number is equal to 2, if it is then we know that it is the repeated number. If it is not 2 but it is 0 we know that it is the skiped number.</description></item><item><title>Leetcode 4</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 14:20:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-4/</guid><description>4. Median of Two Sorted Arrays
The idea of this solution is pretty simple, first append all the nums2 values to nums1. Then sort nums1. If there are a even number of values then the median is the middle two numbers added together and divided by 2. An example could be:
input: nums1 = [1,2], nums2 = [3,4] expected output: 2.5
When the two arrays are combined the new array would be [1, 2, 3, 4] and the two middle numbers are 2, and 3.</description></item><item><title>Leetcode 976</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-976/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 13:50:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-976/</guid><description>976. Largest Perimeter Triangle
The idea of this solution is to sort the array and then keep on checking the largest three side lengths.
In the problem it asks us to &amp;ldquo;return the largest perimeter of a triangle with non-zero area.&amp;rdquo; Non-zero area means a triangle with the two smaller side lengths that add up to be greater than the greatest side length. This can be show in a couple images</description></item><item><title>Leetcode 1523</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-1523/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 17:03:24 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-1523/</guid><description>1523. Count Odd Numbers in an Interval Range
The idea of this solution is to get the number odd numbers from 0 to high, and then subtract the number of odd numbers from 0 to low - 1. The idea can be shown by an example:
high: 7 low : 3 The odd numbers from 0 to high (7). There are 4 odd numbers from 0 to 7. The odd numbers from 0 to low - 1 (2).</description></item><item><title>Leetcode 1637</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-1637/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 16:52:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-1637/</guid><description>1637. Widest Vertical Area Between Two Points Containing No Points
points = {x, y} The idea of this solution is to ignore the y part of points because the vertical area is the made of vertical lines. Vertical lines are made up off one x value for every y value. An example could be the line x = 3, this is a vertical line at the x value 3.</description></item></channel></rss>