<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>images on nathan naveen</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/tags/images/</link><description>Recent content in images on nathan naveen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 15:47:24 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nathannaveen.dev/tags/images/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leetcode 347</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-347/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 15:47:24 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-347/</guid><description>347. Top K Frequent Elements
The idea of this solution is pretty simple. First, add all the numbers to a matrix array with the size [number of different elements][2]. Then sort the array, and then add the values to a regular array of size K.
The matrix array has a size of [number of different elemtnets][2] because we need to add every element to its corresponding place in the array and then update the frequency by adding one to it.</description></item><item><title>Leetcode 1636</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-1636/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 16:02:55 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-1636/</guid><description>1636. Sort Array by Increasing Frequency
The main idea of both the solutions is to add all the numbers to a matrix of lengths [len(nums)][2] and then sort each frequency of numbers by the max frequency. Suppose two values have the same frequency sort them by the value in descending order. After they are sorted, add all the values back to nums and return nums.
This is the sort:
for i := 1; i &amp;lt; len(arr); i++ { if i &amp;gt;= 1 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ((arr[i-1][0] &amp;gt; arr[i][0]) || (arr[i-1][0] == arr[i][0] &amp;amp;&amp;amp; arr[i-1][1] &amp;lt; arr[i][1])) { arr[i], arr[i-1] = arr[i-1], arr[i] i -= 2 } } The idea of it is to start at the second item (first if 0 indexed) and then check whether the frequency of the number before the current is greater than the frequency of the current number.</description></item><item><title>Leetcode 459</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-459/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 14:46:05 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-459/</guid><description>459. Repeated Substring Pattern
The idea of this solution is any substring that is repeated throughout the string s has to start at the 0&amp;lsquo;th index and end at another index, such as the 3&amp;lsquo;ed. This can be shown by using a image.
In both the examples the substrings that are repeated are green.
In the first example the substring abc starts at the 0&amp;lsquo;th index and ends at the 2&amp;rsquo;d index.</description></item><item><title>Leetcode 946</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-946/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 10:59:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-946/</guid><description>The idea of this solution is to append the pushed value to the stack. If peeked value is equal to the poped value then pop it off the stack, keep poping off the peeked value if it is equal to the poped value. This can be show in an image
func validateStackSequences(pushed []int, popped []int) bool { stack := []int{} popCounter := 0 for i := 0; i &amp;lt; len(pushed); i++ { stack = append(stack, pushed[i]) for len(stack) !</description></item><item><title>Leetcode 1704</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-1704/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 20:22:25 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-1704/</guid><description>The idea of this solution is to first make the input string lowercase, and then add 1 to an integer array at the index of every letter, a = 0, b = 1, c = 2.... First we add to the array called first, then starting at a certain index start adding it to second.
After that, add the number of vowel that have occured. The code does this by doing</description></item><item><title>Leetcode 1296</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-1296/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 15:47:35 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-1296/</guid><description>Divide array in sets of k consecutive numbers
The idea of this solution is to loop over the nums array until all the values are -1. The reason they all will become negative one is, whenever a item is used the value will become -1 so the code knows to not use that number again.
If you didn&amp;rsquo;t understand the explanation this can be shown using the code on the bottom, an example and some pictures: By the way sorry if my handwriting is messy</description></item><item><title>Leetcode 1566</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-1566/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 15:46:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-1566/</guid><description>1566. Detect Pattern of Length M Repeated K or More Times The idea of this can be show by this image
func containsPattern(arr []int, m int, k int) bool { counter := 0 for i := 0; i &amp;lt; len(arr) - m; i++ { if arr[i] != arr[i+m] { counter = 0 } else { counter++ } if counter == (k-1)*m { return true } } return false }</description></item><item><title>Leetcode 976</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-976/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 13:50:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-976/</guid><description>976. Largest Perimeter Triangle
The idea of this solution is to sort the array and then keep on checking the largest three side lengths.
In the problem it asks us to &amp;ldquo;return the largest perimeter of a triangle with non-zero area.&amp;rdquo; Non-zero area means a triangle with the two smaller side lengths that add up to be greater than the greatest side length. This can be show in a couple images</description></item><item><title>Leetcode 1523</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-1523/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 17:03:24 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-1523/</guid><description>1523. Count Odd Numbers in an Interval Range
The idea of this solution is to get the number odd numbers from 0 to high, and then subtract the number of odd numbers from 0 to low - 1. The idea can be shown by an example:
high: 7 low : 3 The odd numbers from 0 to high (7). There are 4 odd numbers from 0 to 7. The odd numbers from 0 to low - 1 (2).</description></item><item><title>Leetcode 1637</title><link>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-1637/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 16:52:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://nathannaveen.dev/posts/leetcode-1637/</guid><description>1637. Widest Vertical Area Between Two Points Containing No Points
points = {x, y} The idea of this solution is to ignore the y part of points because the vertical area is the made of vertical lines. Vertical lines are made up off one x value for every y value. An example could be the line x = 3, this is a vertical line at the x value 3.</description></item></channel></rss>